American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf. 1866-1886 APS.Archives.IIf APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 25, 1886; 8x5; Sargent, Charles Sprague, 1841-1927
    Brookline, Mass., A.L.S. 1p.,end.,and end. Asking for article by [G.] Engelmann.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 26, 1886; 8x5; Hugunin, Henry M.
    Chicago, A.L.S. 2p. Suggesting a change in the calendar in accordance with the natural division of the seasons.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 27, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Estes & Lauriat
    Boston, L. 1p. Enc.wanting. Financial matter.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Jan. 29, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S.in 3rd.P. 1p.,end. Asking for favor. Financial matter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 2, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning illustrating plate for his paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 2, 1886; 8x5; Beehler, William Henry, 1848-1915
    Wash., D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Offers for sale his book on the cruise of the ship Brooklyn.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 3, 1886; 8x5; Royal Society of Tasmania
    A.L.S.:Alex[ander] Morton,librarian. 1p. and end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 4, 1886; 8x5; Napier, John T.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Order for publication by [E.] McCauley.
  - Letter to He[n]ry Phillips, Feb. 4, 1886; 10x8; Megargee, S. Edwin
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Says the above-named case is the first on Monday's list and will certainly be reached.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 8, 1886; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning notices for meeting.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Feb. 8, 1886; 8x5; Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México. Observatorio Astronómico Nacional
    Tacubaya, Printed L. filled in in ms. s.: Angel Anguiano 1p. Partly in Spanish. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 9, 1886; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.and end. Appoints Frazer, Law, Horn, Brinton, and McKean to committee on the state of the Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 10, 1886; 3x5; Stokes, Alfred C.
    Trenton, N.J., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Asking for copies of his papers.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 10, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the meeting of the committee [on the state of the Society]. Refers to [F.] Fraley.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Feb. 12, 1886; 5x3; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S.with rubber stamp. 1p.and add. Has received a request for a list of the Society's members.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 13, 1886; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends his own manuscript on El Shedi, and a paper by [J.] Branner. Order for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 13, 1886; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Asking for favor in connection with his paper. Refers to [J.] Branner.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 15, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning the meeting of the special committee on the state of the Society.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 15, 1886; 10x8; Macadam, R. K.
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Asking for publication on botany by [L.de] Schweinitz. Refers to Isaac and Thomas lea.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 16, 1886; 3-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning W. Sellers' obituary of G. Whitney.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 16, 1886; 5x8; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, L. 1p.and end. Enc.wanting. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 16, 1886; 8x5; Royal Society of London
    London, A.L.S.:Herbert Rix. 2p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to J.P[eter] Lesley, Feb. 17, 1886; 11x8-1/2; Herrick, C. L. (Clarence Luther), 1858-1903
    Granville, Ohio, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Exchanges. Encloses a prospectus of Denison university's Bulletin of the scientific laboratories (see in printed catalogue).
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Feb. 18, 1886; 8x5; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p. Asking about publication. On same sheet is note from J.P.Lesley to [Henry Phillips], [Feb., 1886].
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 18, 1886; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Asking that the title of his paper [on horses] be announced at the next meeting of the Society.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 18, 1886; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the obituary of [G.] Whitney.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 19, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Harper, Francis P. (Francis Perego), 1856?-1932
    New York, L.S. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 21, 1886; 11x9; Winkler, Clemens Alexander, 1838-1904
    Freiberg, A.L.S. 2p.,end. In German. Announcing his discovery of the chemical element Germanium.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 25, 1886; 10-1/2x8; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    [Phila.], T.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for change in the Laws and Regulations of the Society pertaining to the lending of books and pamphlets.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Feb. 25, 1886; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology
    Wash.,D.C., T.L.S.:James C.Pilling. 1p.,end. Order for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 25, 1886; 10x8; Macadam, R. K.
    Boston, A.L.S 1p.,end. Desires copies of APS publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 25, 1886; 8x5; Royal Statistical Society (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.:J[oseph] Whittall,secretary. 2p., end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 26, 1886; 10-1/2x8; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    [Phila.], T.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning the lending of books by the Society.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 27, 1886; 10x7; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning publications. Refers to [J.P.] Lesley.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 27, 1886; 12-1/2x8; Hughes, Thomas Patrick, 1838-1911
    Lebanon Springs, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Offers for sale to Society his Dictionary of Islam.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 28, 1886; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Peary, Robert E. (Robert Edwin), 1856-1920
    A.L. 1p. Enc.wanting. Mutilated. Asking about articles on Arctic subjects which may have appeared in the Society's publications.
  - Note to [Henry Phillips, Feb., 1886; 8x5; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.N.S. 1p. Relative to [J.] Branner's question. On same sheet as letter from John C.Branner to Prof.J.P.Lesley, Feb.18, 1886.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 4, 1886; 8x5; Leeds Philosophical & Literary Society
    A.L.S.:W[illia]m Eagle Clarke. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry C.[sic] Phillips, March 5, 1886; 8x5; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 5, 1886; 8x5; Hallowell, Mrs.
    Phila., A.L.in 3rd.P. 2p. Enc.wanting. Returns catalogue. Concerning John Chapman, and Princess Romanoff [Ekaterina R.Daschkow].
  - Letter to S[amuel] S.Lewis, Cambridge, [Eng.], March 6, 1886; 3x5; William Wesley & Son
    London, L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Have no information about the parcel. H.Phillips and the Smithsonian institution are mentioned. This was originally pasted on: Smithsonian institution. Price list...; 1882.
  - Letter to J. Sergeant Price, March 8, 1886; 8x5; Wister, Owen J. (Owen Jones), 1825-1896
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asking about his membership status in the Society. Enclosed originally in letter from J.S. Price to [Henry] Phillips, March 11, 1886.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], March 10, 1886; 11x8-1/2; Institut Canadien-français d'Ottawa
    Ottawa, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.:F.R.E. Campeau, president. 1p.,end.,and calling card. In French. Requesting exchanges. Enclosed is a prospectus concerning the Institut (see in Broadside collection).
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 11, 1886; 8x5; Hamilton, James McLure, 1853-1936
    A.L.S. 1p. Sends chair, given by Joseph Napoleon to Nathaniel Chapman, as gift from his father.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 11, 1886; 5x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p. Enc. Concerning O.J.Wister's membership status in the Society. For enclosure, see letter from Owen J. Wister to J.S.Price, March 8, 1886.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 12, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for loan of Harvard publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 18, 1886; 8x5; Hale, Edward Everett, 1863-1932
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Encloses inventory of articles in the chest. Thanks for accommodations.
  - Memorandum to the American philosophical society, March 18, 1886; 11x8-1/2; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.D.S. 1p. Offers resolution placing the Lackawanna institute of science on the Society's list of correspondents.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 22, 1886; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    A.L.S. 1p. Asking for data on members of Society.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 24, 1886; 8x5; Murray, Joseph A. (Joseph Alexander), 1815-1889
    Carlisle, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for publication. Refers to article by [J.P.] Lesley. Discusses his own attempt to purchase Hebrew Bible.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 24, 1886; 8x5; Schele de Vere, M. (Maximilian), 1820-1898
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 25, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Holland, James W. (James William), 1849-1922
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for Publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 26, 1886; 8x5; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 31, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lagen, Charles Augustus, 1849-1916
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Concerning [Henry S.?] Hagert.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 2, 1886; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Presenting H.Osborn's paper for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 2, 1886; 10-1/2x8; Elliot, S. Sowell
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April [2], 1886; 7x4-1/2; Hockley, Thomas, 1839-1892
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end.,and end. Change of address. A change of address for D.R.Goodwin is mentioned in an endorsement.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 3, 1886; 3x5; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning Society's publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 10, 1886; 3x5; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 10, 1886; 11x8-1/2; Oneida Historical Society at Utica
    Utica, N.Y., Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:C[harles] W[illiam] Darling. 1p.and end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 12, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Winship, Richard C.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Wishes to consult the publications of the Essex institute in the Society's library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 13, 1886; 11x8-1/2; Oneida Historical Society at Utica
    Utica, N.Y., A.L.S.:C[harles] W.Darling. 1p. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 16, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; France. Ministère de l'agriculture, du commerce et des travaux publics
    Paris, L.S.:[Charles] R[ené] Zeiller. 2p.,end. In French. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 17, 1886; 5-1/2x9-1/2; Randall, J. S.
    Georgetown, Colo., T.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for F.Genth's article on the minerals of Colorado.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 19, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Simpson, H. D. Howden
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for article on Coleoptera by J.L.LeConte and [G.] Horn.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 20, 1886; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the Royal Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 20, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning the file of composite signatures [for his paper], and his colored map of York County, [Pa.].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 21, 1886; 8x5; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Has sent the second part of his article on the Beothuk language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 21, 1886; 11x8; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,and end.by Guy Hinsdale. Asking for return of his copper plate map of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to J.P[eter] Lesley, April 22, 1886; 8x5; Seher, Thomas
    St.Vincent College, Pa., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Requesting article by [G.] Horn on Curculionidae.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 25, 1886; 11x7-1/2; Musée Guimet (Lyon, France)
    Lyon, L.S.:[Leon] de Milloué. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 26, 1886; 11x8-1/2; Institut Canadien-français d'Ottawa
    Ottawa, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:N.Boulet. 1p.,end. Mutilated. Partly in French. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 27, 1886; 3x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning a paper of his which is wanted by [T] Seher.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 30, 1886; 10x7-1/2; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for copies of his article on the Lackawanna Valley, and for maps.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 3, 1886; 8x5; Bollman, Charles H. (Charles Harvey), 1868-1889
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for Meinert's article on Myriapoda.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 5, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning E.Suess. Concerning his map, and plate for paper on Composite [photography]. Refers to W.C.Taylor.
  - Letter to E[dward] Y.McCauley, Phila., May 6, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hiersemann, Karl W.
    Leipzig, [?]. A.L.S. 1p.and add., and add.,end. Order for article on Egyptology.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 8, 1886; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Order for Society's publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 14, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends paper [on the genera of snakes].
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 14, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends two drawings for his paper on Amphiumidae.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 15, 1886; 11x9; Verein für Vaterländische Naturkunde in Württemberg. Stuttgart. Jahreshefte
    Stuttgart, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:F[erdinand] Krauss. 1p.,end. Partly in German. Thanks for publications. Order for publications.
  - Lettert to Henry Phillips, May 24, [1886?]; 8x5; Bell, I. Lowthian (Isaac Lowthian), 1816-1904
    Northallerton, [Eng.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a mistake on the title page of his work on the iron trade.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 24, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends statement which he should like approved and transmitted to [J.S.] Price.
  - Letter to Prof. J. P[eter] Lesley, May 24, 1886; 10x8; Mallery, Garrick, 1831-1894
    Wash., D.C., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Asking if the Society wishes his photograph.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 25, 1886; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning an estimate for his illustrations.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 28, 1886; 8x5; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, A.L.S.:Frank B[utler] Gay,secretary. 1p.,end.,and end. Order for publication.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 28, 1886; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning his paper on Amphiumidae.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 28, 1886; 8x5; Mallery, Garrick, 1831-1894
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends his photograph.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 31, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends W.Curtis Taylor's file for the plate of composite signatures.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 1, 1886; 3x5; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, A.L.on postal card S.:Frank B.Gay,secretary 1p.and add.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G.Brinton, June 2, 1886; 3x5; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Wants him to see that the publication committee of the Society passes on [E.D.] Cope's paper.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 3, 1886; 8-1/2x3-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking him to notify members of the publication committee of the Society about a meeting.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 4, 1886; 10x8; United States. Dept. of the Interior
    Wash.,D.C., Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:H.L.Muldrow. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 8, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 10, 1886; 9-1/2x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning a change of wording in Dr. F's [Persifor Frazer's] paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 12, 1886; 10-1/2x8; Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:Arthur Berry, collector. 1p. Request for proof on free entry of books intended for the Society.
  - Letter to collector of the port of New York City, New York, June 15, 1886; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., T.L.S.:Henry Phillips,secretary. 1p.and end. Copy. Concerning free entry on books.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 16, 1886; 7x4-1/2; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    London, A.L.S. 3p.,end.,and end. Declines membership in the Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 16, 1886; 10x8; Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, L.S.:Geo[rge] Wright. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning free entry on books.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 17, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Wilcox, William A. (William Alonzo), b. 1857
    Scranton, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for copy of the Society's Laws and Regulations for a friend.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 19, 1886; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Columbia Co.,N.Y., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends manuscript on Bufo and Rana.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 20, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking about the status of his two plates for the Transactions.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], June 21, 1886; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking him to get the work started on his plates.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 21, 1886; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., T.L.S.:S[pencer] F.Baird,secretary. 1p. Concerning a receipt for an exchange package received by the Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 22, 1886; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking for names and addresses of members elected to Society since Jan.1, 1886.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 22, 1886; 10x8; Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, A.L.S.:Geo[rge] Wright. 1p. Authorization for the free entry on books has been made.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 24, 1886; 10x8; Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, L.S.:Arthur Berry. 1p. Enc.wanting. Is returning the oath respecting the Society's act of incorporation, as it is not a proper from.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 25, 1886; 11x8-1/2; American public library, Frankfurt, Ger.
    Frankfurt, A.L.S.:Carl Lautenschlager,manager. lp.,end. Enc. Concerning his library. Requesting donation of the Society's publications. Enclosure is an advertisement about the library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 28, 1886; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Requesting [Eli K.Price's] obituary of John Read for his son, Gen.Read.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 29, 1886; 10x8; Alexander Hamilton United States Custom House (New York, N.Y.)
    New York, A.L.S.:Arthur Berry. 1p. Confirms receipt of the Society's copy of its charter, for his office's records.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 1, 1886; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking if John Napier has been elected to membership in Society, as [H.] Trumbull has paid his admission fee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 3, 1886; 10-1/2x8; New York Academy of Sciences
    New York, A.L.S.:H[erman] L.Fairchild,secretary. 1p.,end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 8, 1886; 8x5; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, A.L.S.: Austin Holden. 3p.,end. Concerning Publications. Refers to memoir by (A.) Agassiz.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 9, 1886; 9-1/2x6; McIlvaine, Charles
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Inquiring for a friend about an article by [L.de] Schweinitz.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, July 9, 1886?; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lagen, Charles Augustus, 1849-1916
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning petition. Concerning [H.S.?] Hagert.
  - Letter to J. Sergeant Price, July 12, 1886; 9x5-1/2; Philadelphia. Department of markets & city property
    Phila., L.S.:William Dixey,commissioner. 1p. Concerning repairs to Philosophical Hall and the jury rooms.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, July 13, 1886; 8x4-1/2; Taylor, W. Curtis, co.
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for payment of their bill against the Society. Refers to [P.] Frazer. (On back of letter is notation of no apparent relevance).
  - Note to the American philosophical society, July 14, 1886; 3x5; Foote, Albert E., 1846-1895
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p.and end. Asking that bearer receive a copy of [G.] Horn's article on Tenebrionidae. FILM403 FRAME97
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, July 14, 1886; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lagen, Charles Augustus, 1849-1916
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning [H.S.?] Hagert. Concerning petition.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 14, 1886; 9-1/2x7-1/2; United States. Dept. of the Interior
    Wash.,D.C., L.S.:H.L.Muldrow. 1p.and end. Is sending the publications asked for.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 15, 1886; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    White Earth, Minn., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the Ojibwa Indians.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 16, 1886; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897